<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>PHACK on Tchoupapps-fr</title><link>https://tchoupapps.fr/posts/phack21/</link><description>Recent content in PHACK on Tchoupapps-fr</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>fr-fr</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 07:56:06 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tchoupapps.fr/posts/phack21/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>SUDOKU</title><link>https://tchoupapps.fr/posts/phack21/sudoku/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 13:48:21 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://tchoupapps.fr/posts/phack21/sudoku/</guid><description>Sudoku First we connect via ssh with given login/password
We when connect, we are prompted with a message :
I checked the rights on the flag file :
We can see that only user master can read the file. It means that we have to do some kinds of privilege escalations in order to read the file.
First thing that come to my mind is to check if there is some commands that we are able to run as others users.</description></item><item><title>GRADUATED</title><link>https://tchoupapps.fr/posts/phack21/graduated/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 13:37:51 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://tchoupapps.fr/posts/phack21/graduated/</guid><description>Graduated First we connect via ssh with given login/password
We when connect, we are prompted with a message :
I checked the rights /home/rector directory
We can see that only user master can read the flag file but we can see a lot of different file that are readable for us.
I still check if there is some commands that we are able to run as others users and I also check the SUID for binaries file .</description></item><item><title>BEN HARRY</title><link>https://tchoupapps.fr/posts/phack21/ben-harry/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 13:23:23 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://tchoupapps.fr/posts/phack21/ben-harry/</guid><description>Ben &amp;amp; Harry We have to go on the website : ben-and-harry.phack.fr:1664
We can see three informations, &amp;ldquo;b&amp;rdquo; ,&amp;ldquo;code&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;msg&amp;rdquo;
The msg is asking us to answer it so after a while, we manage to understand that the &amp;ldquo;b&amp;rdquo; variable is the base used for the number. So our guess is to decrypt using the base and then send back to the server the answer.
Here is the python script :</description></item><item><title>WIKIBOT</title><link>https://tchoupapps.fr/posts/phack21/wikibot/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 21:03:14 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://tchoupapps.fr/posts/phack21/wikibot/</guid><description>WikiBot Description Solve Nous avons un lien vers le discord du CTF.
Après avoir envoyer un DM au bot, celui-ci, nous demande de répondre à une série de questions en moins de 3 secondes.
Pour résoudre ce challenge, je vais utilisé mon compte Discord pour communiquer avec ce bot à travers l&amp;rsquo;API discord.
J&amp;rsquo;ai donc besoin de DiscordPy pour mon programme en python.
J&amp;rsquo;ai besoin de deux informations, pour pouvoir communiquer avec le bot.</description></item><item><title>RAID DEAD REDEMPTION</title><link>https://tchoupapps.fr/posts/phack21/raid-dead-redemption/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 20:01:53 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://tchoupapps.fr/posts/phack21/raid-dead-redemption/</guid><description>Raid Dead Redemption Description Solve Nous avons deux fichiers:
NoticeMastok_3000.pdf un pdf contenant une documentation technique. Un zip, contenant trois fichiers binaires DISK1.bin, DISK2.bin et DISK3.bin. Je fait une petite analyse rapide de ces fichiers:
$ ls -l -rw-rw-r-- 1 chapeaurouge chapeaurouge 662835 Dec 10 07:56 DISK1.bin -rw-rw-r-- 1 chapeaurouge chapeaurouge 0 Dec 10 07:56 DISK2.bin -rw-rw-r-- 1 chapeaurouge chapeaurouge 662835 Dec 10 07:56 DISK3.bin Je remarque que le fichier DISK2.</description></item></channel></rss>